Guide to the Loomis-Wilder Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- JOHN AUGUSTUS WILDER (1836?-1870), 1843-1870, 1909; Series V
  - Special Files
    - Personal, Legal, and Financial Documents
      - North Carolina district court: admission as attorney: June, 1866 (Box 33, Folder 89)
      - Purchase of Kansas City Journal of Commerce: financial and legal papers, 1867 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Financial papers: bills, etc., Kansas City, 1866-1870 (Box 33, Folder 91)
      - Funeral arrangements and expenses, 1866-1870 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Estate of John A. Wilder
        See: Letters from Twiss, Stephen and Foster C. to Loomis, E.J., Loomis, M.W., and Wilder, M.W.F.J. See also: box 8, folder 92 See also: box 24, folder 72 See also: box 26, folder 27
    - Diaries, Notebooks
      - Note and account book (mostly blank), Circa 1852-1856 (Box 33, Folder 93)
      - Childhood commonplace book: pages, Circa 1848-1849 (Box 33, Folder 93a)
      - Pocket diaries: 1) Union College (ca. 1854-1856), 2) 1857-1859, 1854-1856, 1857-1859 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Pocket diary, 1867 (Box 33, Folder 95)
    - Education
      - Book of college lecture notes, surveying, etc., 1854 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - College essays and original writings, 1853-1856 (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - College notes and essays: history, politics, 1853-1856 (Box 33, Folder 98)
      - College notes: math, science, 1853-1856 (Box 33, Folder 99)
      - College notes: languages, 1853-1855 (Box 33, Folder 100)
      - Law School notes and notebook, 1856-1857 (Box 34, Folder 101)
      - Law School notes, 1856-1857 (Box 34, Folder 102)
    - Professional
      - Practice as Boston attorney: legal papers, 1857-1862 (Box 34, Folder 103)
    - Writings
      - Columns on Boston and area, Cambridge Chronicle, August-October 1855 (Box 34, Folder 104)
      - "Will the American Experiment Fail?" Union College Commencement Speech, July 23, 1856 (Box 34, Folder 105)
      - Writings on Union College, prob. by J.A.W., 1856 and undated (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Columns in Cambridge Chronicle, pseudonym "Prospect Street" —on New York state and Maine, 1856 (Box 34, Folder 107)
      - "A Trip through Cortland, Tompkins, and Tioga," Syracuse Standard, Sept. 11, 1856 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - "A visit to the Dane Law School," Cambridge Chronicle, Circa November 1857 (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - "Everything Has Its Price," Cambridge High School Association 7th Annual Reunion Oratory, 1859 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Miscellaneous pieces in Cambridge Chronicle, mainly about local affairs, Undated (late 1850's, early 1860's) (Box 34, Folder 111)
      - "The Great Cambridge Telescope," Cambridge Chronicle, Undated (ca. 1862?) (Box 34, Folder 112)
      - Newspaper reports by J.A.W. from Fortress Monroe (1862) and Key Key West, Florida (1864), 1862, 1864 (Box 34, Folder 113)
      - Drafts of article (?) on Key West, Florida, Undated (post 1864) (Box 34, Folder 114)
      - Editorial, Kansas City Journal of Commerce, 1868 May 29 (Box 34, Folder 115)
      - "Out on the Reef," Atlantic Monthly, August 1868 (Box 34, Folder 116)
      - "The Wedding at Parker House" Putnam's Monthly Magazine, August 1868 (Box 34, Folder 117)
      - Address at opening Kansas City, Mo., College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1869 (Box 34, Folder 118)
      - Short drafts, letters to editors, etc., mostly undated(ca. 1854-1868) (Box 34, Folder 119)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Notes, invitations, writings of others, printed matter (Union College), 1852-1856 (Box 34, Folder 120)
      - Notes invitations, writings of others, printed matter (Cambridge Mass.), 1857-1862 (Box 34, Folder 121)
      - Notes invitations, printed matter, writings of others (Kansas City), 1866-1870 and undated (Box 34, Folder 122)
  - Microfilm
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and juvenile writings, ca. 1840s, kept by John Augustus Wilder in an invoice and letterbook of the G and H [Company?] of Boston. The clippings have been removed from the book and destroyed, and the book is separately catalogued as Account Books Misc. 4, filmed 1972
    - Regimental order book of Charles Baker Wilder as superintendent of contrabands at Fort Monroe, Virginia, which contains general and special orders and correspondence with the War Department, regarding problems connected with contrabands and their care, 1862 Mar-1865 Feb. The orderbook is included in Folio I of the Loomis-Wilder Family papers, filmed 1980
- OVERSIZE, Series VI
  - Loomis, Nathan: commonplace book, 1819 July (Box 35)
  - Loomis, Eben Jenks: bound volume of The Home Magazine, containing EJL's articles; "Astronomical Distances" and "The Modern: Way,", 1888 November-1889 October (Box 35)
  - Wilder, Charles B.
    - Regimental order book, 1862 March - 1865 February (Box 35)
  - Wilder, John Augustus
    - Diploma from Adelphi Society, Union College, 1856 (Box 35)
    - Certificate from Cambridge Academy (Harvard Law School), 1858 (Box 25)
  - Loomis, Eben Jenks: scrapbook of greetings received for 80th birthday, 1908 November 11 (Box 36)